Kazi Noshin

Katabon, Bangladesh

■+8801559500533 | ■kazi.noshin.111@gmail.com | 🎢 noshinxd.github.io/KN_nortfolio/ | 🖸 https://github.com/NoshinXD

Personal Profile

I am a recent Computer Science and Engineering graduate. I am currently working as a Lecturer at the Department of Computer Science and Engineering, University of Asia Pacific. Apart from my professional career, I am enthusiastic about research works in Machine learning, Deep learning, Medical AI, and related fields.

Education

Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (BUET)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

Feb 2017 - May 2022

• CGPA: 3.68/4.00

Ideal School and College

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Higher Secondary Certificate, Science

July 2014 - June 2016

• GPA: 5.00/5.00

Ideal School and College

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Secondary School Certificate, Science

2004 - 2014

• GPA: 5.00/5.00

Work Experience _____

University of Asia Pacific

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Aug 2022 - Present

· Courses Teaching:

Lecturer

- Structured Programming (C)
- Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Methodology Lab
- Software Development
- Challenging Responsibilities:
 - Efficient planning of assignments to enhance the student's ability to understand computer basics.

BUET-Japan Institute of Disaster Prevention and Urban Safety

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Research Assistant

Supervisor: Dr. Mohammed Eunus Ali (BUET)

July 2022 - Present

- Purpose:
 - Improvement of Earthquake Early Warning System using graph attention networks

Research Projects _____

Actionable analytics of cancer

2021-Current

Supervisor: Dr. Mohammad Saifur Rahman (BUET)

External Collaborator: Dr. Abu Zafer Mohammed Dayem Ullah (Barts Cancer Institute)

- · Identifying the association of various clinical or molecular factors with the survival of patients diagnosed with cancers.
- Using machine learning techniques to develop a gene mutation-based scoring system for categorizing patients according to their survival potential

Parkinson's Analysis with Remote Tasks

2021 - 2022

Supervisor: Dr. Mohammad Saifur Rahman (BUET)

External Collaborators: Dr. Imran Sarker (NINH, Bangladesh), Dr. Ehsan Hoque (University of Rochester)

- Building a simple automated online PD screening tool by modifying an existing web-based application that can capture audio and video data from participants to identify Parkinson's Disease (PD) in thousands of undiagnosed people in Bangladesh. The goal is to give patients the opportunity for frequent assessment/monitoring without having to schedule neurologists or require them to travel to a healthcare facility.
- Studying the status of people with Parkinson's disease in Bangladesh, using our machine learning-based models.
- Contributing to the ongoing study to improve the condition of the 10 million people worldwide who currently have Parkinson's disease.

Notable Projects_____

November 29, 2022

WBC classification

Deep Learning Project 2022

• This project classifies four subtypes of white blood cells from the image data of blood cells.

· Framework: Keras

CNN from Scratch

Deep Learning Project 2022

- Implemented a convolutional neural network from scratch for an image classification task.
- · Language: Python

DNS cache poisoning

Network Security Project

· An attacker can poison the DNS cache and direct users to a false website in order to gain personal the information which will be a phishing attack

• Language: C, Tool: VirtualBox VM, WireShark

SHIKHON - The Admission Helper

Software Development Project

- The targeted users of the platform is University Admission Candidates and the purpose of the application is to provide tutorials, notes, and solutions about a particular topic of a particular subject. The main challenge of this project is to learn how to build an interactive live application.
- · Language: Javascript, Library: NodeJS, Database: MongoDB, Frontend: React Native JS

Lines Of Action (LOA)

Artificial Intelligence Project

2021

- This project provides a platform where the player can play with an AI agent or two players can play with each other.
- · Language: Java, Framework: Slick

Skills

Programming Python, R, C/C++, Java, javascript, BashScript, HTML, CSS, AWK, TCL

Database PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Frameworks Keras, PyTorch, Node.js, React.js, React-native, Bootstrap, Javafx, Slick, OpenGL

Git, Microsoft Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Figma, MATLAB, Latex, Adobe XD (UI/UX Design), Wireshark, Cisco Packet Tracer, Linux Tools/Software

Libraries Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, SciPy, Scikit-Learn, TensorFlow, OpenFace

English Proficiency

TOEFL Reading: 26, Listening: 26, Speaking: 22, Writing: 27

Achievements

FE Certificate, Fundamental IT Engineer (FE) level -2 Examination (passed both shifts)

Bangladesh

2009-2016 Merit Scholarship, Primary School, Junior School, Secondary School, and Higher Secondary Certificate

Dhaka Board

Interests

Baking I like to bake home-style cream cakes.

Drama Direction I directed some dramas at my university functions.

Music I enjoy almost all types of music. I also can play violin at beginner level.

References_____

Dr. Mohammad Saifur Rahman Associate Professor, CSE, BUET, email: mrahman@cse.buet.ac.bd **Dr. Mohammed Eunus Ali** Professor, CSE, BUET, email: mohammed.eunus.ali@gmail.com

NOVEMBER 29, 2022